<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>fictionaries on the papers</title>
    <link>https://thepapers.newbend.art/fictionaries/</link>
    <description>Recent content in fictionaries on the papers</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 05:10:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://thepapers.newbend.art/fictionaries/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>sigrid</title>
      <link>https://thepapers.newbend.art/fictionaries/sigrid/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 05:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thepapers.newbend.art/fictionaries/sigrid/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When I met her, she knew I had this power to go back in time with my camera. She&amp;rsquo;d let me have whatever I needed as long as when I went back, I photographed Sigrid. She wanted to see her long flowing dark brown hair and large brown eyes again. The woman was tending a field wearing a pair of overalls and a bandanna.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I parked my truck, out of habit, in my old parking spot. I liked parking a little far away from my door back then just to get a little more exercise in. I walked in to greet Luke where it was cozy and dark. He mentioned something about the others showing up and asked why I parked so far away. There was a lot of snow on the ground, so it could have been dangerous to walk up hill like that. &amp;ldquo;I used to live here, you know?&amp;rdquo; Not in that very apartment, but down in 1007 for about a year, then I moved over to 1195. Luke was somewhere in between, and I had already forgotten. I knew the others would be here soon. The anticipation of swapping gifts was swimming in the air.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>chelbur</title>
      <link>https://thepapers.newbend.art/fictionaries/chelbur/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 10:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thepapers.newbend.art/fictionaries/chelbur/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When they&amp;rsquo;d pull up to the mail box, she&amp;rsquo;d come running out from under the pool deck pretending to chase after something. Probably a squirrel. She somehow knew that dogs were supposed to keep guard of the house and keep rodents away. She took after her daddy, I think. Calm and gentle most of the time, but would get real serious when she needed to. You didn&amp;rsquo;t really know what she was thinking half the time because of how stoic she was.&#xA;I remember when we got them other dogs, she was not happy. She changed. She knew that they were suddenly more important than her. She kept more quiet most the time, but overall seemed more on edge. She especially didn&amp;rsquo;t like Parker, hardly anyone did. Emmie was fine most of the time, but she started actually killing rodents rather than just chasing them off. Their dad kept voicing concerns about them killing cats, or worse. Even Shelby started killing. She had never done nothing like that before. One time, back by the plum trees, there was something happening. All three of them were growling and making horrible noises, screeching, sounded like something from a horror movie. Once the folks got over there, they saw what was making that horrible noise and why. They&amp;rsquo;d gotten a raccoon.&#xA;Later that week it was just back to Shelby. The other dogs had posed too much a risk of rabies, and were a bad influence on her. They taught her how to get outside of the fence, had her killing animals, and overall just made her more on edge. She still wasn&amp;rsquo;t the same. Even more stoic than before, she lived quite quietly after they left. One thing she never forgot was how her Mama would pat the bench that squeaked so loud each time it was hit, she&amp;rsquo;d come from wherever she was and lay down on that bench. She was taught because in the middle of the night, she&amp;rsquo;d start barking at something beyond her fence. Probably an owl or something. So Mama would pat the bench and holler out, &amp;ldquo;Chellllll-burrrrrr,&amp;rdquo; to which she&amp;rsquo;d come running and lay down quietly and go to bed on that bench.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>number one dad</title>
      <link>https://thepapers.newbend.art/fictionaries/number-one-dad/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 22:23:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thepapers.newbend.art/fictionaries/number-one-dad/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a kind of peace that comes in the autumn. The air smells clearer and feels crisp. Being swallowed up in a quilted duster made just for the wedding, and sipping good pour-over from my #1 DAD mug. Computer stuff is super interesting to me. It&amp;rsquo;s fun to learn how to use the computer as much as possible without picking up the mouse. Of course there&amp;rsquo;s things that still require it, but programs like Obsidian and Neovim make it easier. It&amp;rsquo;s really the browser that is the only thing that makes it hard. Oh and that music player. I need a different one, I think. I&amp;rsquo;m still going through the manual little by little to be sure I don&amp;rsquo;t miss anything. I&amp;rsquo;m eager to get to the configuration part where I can tell this system to open different apps based on the key bindings and somehow get rid of the bullshit I don&amp;rsquo;t want like AI and apps that aren&amp;rsquo;t so much for me.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>simple and easy</title>
      <link>https://thepapers.newbend.art/fictionaries/simple-and-easy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 05:16:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thepapers.newbend.art/fictionaries/simple-and-easy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When you put the potatoes in the pot, just go ahead and turn it on high. You’re just boiling them, they ain’t gon’ burn. You need some salt and sometimes I’ll go ahead and throw in some pepper.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Now you don’t have to sit here and watch it or play with it. Just let it boil for a while and come back to check on ‘em. You can tell they’re done when you stick a knife in and if it falls right back into the water.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;After they’re finished, pour off most the water and just start mashin’. Once they all are a little mashed, throw in your butter, some more black pepper, and just keep going ‘til they just as creamy as you like it.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;I don’t always fix gravy, usually only when I make pork chops or something like that. I pour a little broth in the pan to deglaze it, then I start puttin’ my flour in. Sometimes I’ll use cornstarch if that’s all I have, but whatchu don’t wanna do is use biscuit flour. That’ll make it taste too salty. I let the flour cook until it starts turning brown, then I add the rest of my broth or milk or whatever I’m usin’ that night.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>the aerospace</title>
      <link>https://thepapers.newbend.art/fictionaries/the-aerospace/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Aug 2025 14:43:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thepapers.newbend.art/fictionaries/the-aerospace/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My heart&amp;rsquo;s been racing all morning. Will my makeup run, is my hair straightened, is there a uniform or dress code I don&amp;rsquo;t know about? I haven&amp;rsquo;t had a job job before. This place feels sterile and cold, unlike the Piggly Wiggly where I&amp;rsquo;m always seeing somebody I know.&#xA;My boss walked into the room with a big grin on her face, sayin&amp;rsquo; it&amp;rsquo;s good to see me. She asked if I believed any of that stuff about the computers all not working. I told her I didn&amp;rsquo;t know and I reckon we&amp;rsquo;d just have to see.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>a bird of haunting mystery</title>
      <link>https://thepapers.newbend.art/fictionaries/a-bird-of-haunting-mystery/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 May 2025 21:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thepapers.newbend.art/fictionaries/a-bird-of-haunting-mystery/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In Two-Thousand Eleven, I took a small vacation to Connecticut. Just north of New Haven there’s a wonderful pond with a bridge that cuts right through. Although there’s several houses and a hardware store, it’s surprisingly quiet. The water is marshy and there’s a skinny peninsula that runs parallel to the bridge that reminds me of the marshes back home in the Carolinas. The weather was perfect and cool. The heat wave was why I wanted to get out in the first place.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;I remember my arrival caused quite the commotion last time, seemed I was some sort of celebrity to the folks around Connecticut. Wasn’t sure what I’d did or who I’d done but it was a full on paparazzi with their cameras and binoculars tryna get a good look at me any way they could. After a while it got old and I couldn’t relax anymore. I needed to be on my way back home and get some real sleep.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>the sconce</title>
      <link>https://thepapers.newbend.art/fictionaries/the-sconce/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 14:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thepapers.newbend.art/fictionaries/the-sconce/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When the light turns on, everything within a two foot radius illuminates with a warm, candlelight color. The desk&amp;rsquo;s antique brown stain shimmers, the pages of the notebook turn caramel, and the wall tapestry marries forest green tones with light, reflecting it back onto the eyes of the artist. They&amp;rsquo;re taking notes about something, but you can&amp;rsquo;t make it out through the fog that is the dream. You catch a glimpse as they page through that there was a drawing of the very lamp they just flicked on. In their eyes, you can see concern, imagination, and lust.&#xA;A spruce hangs over you as you lean back against the bark. The air smells like autumn leaves, though you&amp;rsquo;re sure it&amp;rsquo;s the middle of winter. &amp;lsquo;Chewink-chewink&amp;rsquo; &amp;rsquo;too-wink, too-wink&amp;rsquo;. There&amp;rsquo;s a towhee.&#xA;The leather of the boots shows its age, the uppers being covered by jeans or another work pant are soft, still with some shine. The toes are worn near-bare to the steel underneath. Mudding around in the soil with your feet, you can feel there&amp;rsquo;s something hard just below the surface. A root of the spruce. Burgeoning from the bark are little branches you pluck off to grow saplings. These trees will build you a fine home someday.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>yesterday</title>
      <link>https://thepapers.newbend.art/fictionaries/yesterday/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2025 14:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thepapers.newbend.art/fictionaries/yesterday/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Since yesterday, I&amp;rsquo;ve been unable to explain what it is I mean to say. In fact, I&amp;rsquo;ve been saying things that I don&amp;rsquo;t mean to say at all. I didn&amp;rsquo;t mean yesterday, I mean&amp;rsquo;t sometime in the last five days. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure exactly how this is happening. If I&amp;rsquo;ve come down with an illness of some kind, giving me brain fog, or if I should consider cutting back on coffee.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>parker house rolls cafe</title>
      <link>https://thepapers.newbend.art/fictionaries/parker-house-rolls-cafe/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2025 11:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://thepapers.newbend.art/fictionaries/parker-house-rolls-cafe/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;d head there every other Sunday right after church. It seemed like it was one of Don&amp;rsquo;s favorites as much as it was my grandsons. They both liked something about circling what they wanted on the menu and handing it off to the waitress. They handed you a card and a golf pencil, now that might be another reason Don liked it so much, sat you down and fixed you a sweet tea with lemon or whatever else you wanted to drink. First section on the card was about bread. Did you want their famous parker house rolls, or did you want cloverleaf rolls? I never wanted to make Mama mad, and to tell you the truth, I didn&amp;rsquo;t much care for the crunchier crust on cloverleaf anyway. Usually the waitress would peak at what you had circled in the bread section before you finished so they could get it on the table faster. Next you picked your meat or if you were just go&amp;rsquo;n have sides. My grandson always gets the cubed steak or the pork ribs. Me and Don both picked whatever chicken they had, usually. You pick your vegetables, two if you got a meat, three if you didn&amp;rsquo;t. And last, you&amp;rsquo;d pick which dessert you were go&amp;rsquo;n have. The best week was also the worst, because you&amp;rsquo;d want all of them: mud pie, pecan pie, or key lime pie.&#xA;Being it a small town, we always managed to run into folks we knew from church or somewhere else around the community. Don could talk to just about anybody, and he would do just that. He would just talk, and I mean talk, and talk, and talk, and talk. You&amp;rsquo;d think he was just about done and he&amp;rsquo;s start talking again, about some other sorry fella he knew and what ailed them. He would go on so long, and in such detail, folks would think they were being rude to the man by excusing themselves. It never bothered him. He was understanding and knew he had more than enough to say.&#xA;Now back on these rolls, they were the softest parker rolls you&amp;rsquo;d ever have and had plenty of butter too. I&amp;rsquo;m sure they put a slice of butter in the middle before they fold them over and put them in the oven. When me an Mama made them, ours are always the slightest bit crispy. The ones at the cafe were just like a sponge. Well, a sponge that if you squished it, it&amp;rsquo;d stay that way and you&amp;rsquo;d have a hard ball of dough again. I wonder what it was they used to put in them rolls that made them so soft like that. It might just be that when you make something yourself, you can see all its flaws all the more clearly. When you&amp;rsquo;re making food for eight, ten, or even the fellowship, you notice when your rolls aren&amp;rsquo;t exactly the way you&amp;rsquo;d want them to be, even if all of them were gone before the cakes were even touched.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
